Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nguyen-nhu-74b56b2b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Employee Engagement
Communication
Labor and Employment Law

Nguyen Nhu

HR Supervisor/HR Manager Biên Hòa, Dong Nai, Vietnam

Summary

Over 15 years of experience in HR field, I am not only having good knowledge about HR activities but also have general knowledge in many fields as Finance, Warehouse, Logistics, Production. My core values and career objective are to apply my skills in the field of Human Resources & Admin, I am looking for a challenging position to utilize my experience, knowledge and abilities that offer professional growth while being resourceful, innovative and flexible which offers me the opportunity for career advancement and further develop my professional skills in accordance with latest advancements within an organization

Experience

FLUID POWER CONTROLS

HR & Admin Manager August 2023 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Binh Duong, Vietnam

Fluid Power and Controls (FPC) is a US company in Vsip I, Binh Duong province, was established in 2007, manufacturer of solenoids and solenoid-controlled valves.

I'm the only person in HR and in charge of all HR & Admin activities as below:

- 1. Recruitment & Training:
- Set the recruitment plan, build/update talent database, evaluate the recruiment effectivenes
- Responsible for record employee profile, welcome on board and orientation training
- Analyze demands of training and developments, update and develop the training policies and processes
- Monitor and evaluate probation period or sign and renew labor contract
 2. C&B:
- Calculate salary, bonus, and benefits for all employees in accordance with the company's salary and bonus procedures and regulations.

- Make reports on the employment situation, insurance report, salary reports, salary analysis and other arising reports due to the request of company and local Authorities
- Survey the salary and rebuilt the salary scale for the adjustment at the end of the year
- Built Admin and HR annual budget.
- 3. HR relations:
- Implement Company regulations and Collective Agreement , Company Handbook
- Develop/update internal rules and regulations
- Deal with complex disciplinary and HR issues
- 4. Others:
- Coordinate with vendor to do the annual environtment and hazadous waste annual.
- Organization company event such as Summer trip and Year End Party...
- Support on stationery and necessary
- · Other job assignment by the BOD

Stolz-Miras HR & Admin Manager June 2019 - May 2023 (4 years)

Vietnam

Stolz Miras was established in 1998 in Ho Chi Minh city, Thu Duc District and relocated in Amata IZ, Bien Hoa, Dong Nai in 2019. Main job: manufacturing, design, fabricate and install metal equipment on behalf of major industrial and assemble client's word wide.

I am responsile of all activies of HR and Administration go smoothly as below: Main works as procedure:

- 1. Recruitment:
- Oversee the recruitment activies inculding planing, posting, advertising, screening CV, scheduling interview, interviewing. Improve and communicate recruitment policies and processes. Ensure that all the vacancies will be filled on time.
- Coordinate to issue Job description for all levels.
- 2. Training:
- Set and update the orientation training program for new hire.
- Create training and development plans
- Analyze demands of training and developments
- Follow and update the tranining result to all employees and BOD
- 3. C&B

- Monitor and evaluate the probationary review, renew labour contract
- Check and approve monthly attendance record.
- Check and approve monthly salary on Fast software.
- Check and approve monthly compulsory insurance.
- Organize performance evaluation
- Survey and submit the salary increase yearly.
- Prepare the annual bonus (13th salary)
- Check and approve for hazardous subsidy.
- Prepare HR&Admin yearly budget.
- 4. HR relation:
- Implement company regulations and collective labor agreements.
- Advise management about labor relationship/labor structure.
- Make periodic reports as required by local authorities and management.
- 5. GA & Administrations:
- In charge of papper work for expat such as work-permit, visa, temporary residence card, driving license
- Organize company event (grand opening/summer trip/year end party...)
- Check and approve stationery and necessary.
- Control lunch service.
- · Control cleaners, security
- Support on HSE job.
- In charge of ISO standard for HRD

Zamil Steel Building Viet Nam Co, LTd Senior HR officer August 2008 - May 2019 (10 years 10 months)

Dong Nai, Viet Nam

Zamil Steel is Zamil Steel Buildings Vietnam Co., Ltd is a joint venture between Zamil Industrial Investment Company and Mitsui & Co., Ltd. Zamil Steel is a global leader in the manufacture of pre-engineered steel buildings.

Main works as procedure:

- 1. Recruitment:
- Receive "personal request form" and get approval
- Searching CVs and checking CVs which suitable to requirement
- Feedback applied candidate about their CV status.
- Having phone's interview in advance, face to face interview
- Evaluation and prepare the offer letter to success candidate
- 2. C&B:
- Follow and control subcontractor.
- Conduct orientation and job training for employees.

- Control HR Database
- Manage performance appraisal for renewing labor contract/after probation.
- Manage Labor contract.
- Claim 24/07 accident insurance.
- Control compulsory insurance/ medical insurance.
- · Control AL & ticket for expat employees.
- 3. GA:
- Support expat employees in work permit issue.
- 4. Training:
- Receive "Training request form" from department.
- Searching and collecting training center (outsource)
- Arrange plan for training.
- Keep training record.
- 5. Others:
- Make monthly HR report to the BOD.
- Make all reports related to HR for Dong Nai Industrial Zones Authority

Dong Sung

HR specialist

June 2008 - August 2008 (3 months)

Dong Nai, Viet Nam

- Payroll
- Social Insurance
- Recruitment
- Admin
- Labour contract
- Visa, passport

Sam Phu Plastic Company

HR specialist

November 2006 - April 2008 (1 year 6 months)

Long Thành, Dong Nai, Vietnam

- Recruit staff.
- Payroll
- · Management labor contacts.
- Do all reports of medical and social insurance.
- Management labor progress
- Management Annual Leave
- Do all reports for Dong Nai Industrial Zones Authority
- · Management stamp.

- Management material
- Management stationery
- Arrangement timetable for the general manager
- Organize all the meetings, entertainment for the company

Full Power Join Stock Company
HR officer
April 2004 - August 2006 (2 years 5 months)
Binh Duong, Vietnam

- Recruit staff
- Pay roll for 1200 workers.
- Management Labor contact
- Management labor progress
- Management Annual Leave
- Do all reports of medical and social insurance.
- Do all reports for Binh Duong Industrial Zones Authority.

Education

HCMC Education BA, English · (2007 - 2010)

Lac Hong University BA, Trade · (2002 - 2007)